KERRY KOVACIK

DATA ANALYST



512-230-4598



kerrykovacik@gmail.com



Austin, TX



www.linkedin.com/in/kerrykovacik/ https://kerrykova.aithub.io/

PROJECTS

www.github.com/Kerrykova

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts Psychology St. Joseph's College

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Excel
Python, SQL, R
Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib
ETL
Tableau
HTML, CSS, JavaScript, D3

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Data analyst experienced in Excel, VBA, Python and SQL with a background in the financial industry. Self-starter driven to dive down the rabbit hole to investigate and solve mysteries and inconsistencies in data and workflows. Well versed in generating reports and findings to executives and stakeholders. Brings a love of learning, coupled with high attention to detail. Plays an integral part of current cross-functional team, applying these skills to research complex and intricate projects, promote collaboration and manage to completion.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

THE DATA ANALYSIS & VISUALIZATION BOOT CAMP University of Texas at Austin / 2018 – 2019

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data and Machine Learning.

WORK EXPERIENCE

ANALYST - INVESTMENTS

Merrill Lynch / Austin, TX / 2013 - Present

Trade investment accounts with over \$400 million in assets under management. Create and analyze reports and visualizations for 401(k) cost-benefit analysis, commissions tracking, business expenses and reimbursements, and assets under management, etc. Collaborate and manage vendors and clients as 401(k) plan liaison for our team.

- Achieved internal Top 100 in Excellence award 5 years running.
- Build reports and workflows for trading of managed portfolios which has led to a reduction in trade errors.
- Diagnose, research and correct data discrepancies and inaccuracies in internal and external systems, tools and reporting resulting in thousands of dollars in financial savings for our clients.

EXECUTIVE ASSISTANT / OFFICE MANAGER

Robert J. Eckhardt & Co., P.C. / Melville, NY / 2006 - 2013

Managed all interoffice operations and processes, such as coordinating multiple teams for tax filing deadlines to ensure no late or missed client submissions to the Internal Revenue Service (IRS).

- Completed individual, sales and payroll taxes as well as W2 and 1099 forms.
- Coded and input expenses to generate financial statements.
- Calculated internal rates of return and assets allocations for financial